neverendingvoyage.com 2019-01-28

# Disclosure and Privacy Policy - Never Ending Voyage

## Disclosures

### Affiliate Links

Some of the links on Never Ending Voyage are affiliate links which means that we receive a small commission if you buy anything through them, at no extra cost to you. We only link to products, hotels and activities that we truly recommend. 

Never Ending Voyage is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com.

### Partnerships 

Occasionally we work with tourist boards, hotels, activity providers, or travel brands to promote destinations, tours, accommodation, gear, etc. We receive compensation such as free services or a fee in exchange for a review on this site.

We retain full editorial control and will always give an honest review of our experiences. We are very selective about the companies we work with and will only recommend products or experiences if we believe they will be of benefit to you. 

All partnerships are disclosed in the relevant blog posts. 

## Privacy Policy

Never Ending Voyage takes your privacy very seriously. We try to minimise the amount of personal information we collect and any information we do collect (such as your email address) are transmitted and stored securely. 

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

## What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?

You may be asked to enter your email address to sign up to our mailing list. You may also be asked for your name and email when leaving a comment. These actions are entirely optional and does not prevent you from accessing the site.

We use Mailchimp as our marketing automation platform. By clicking submit, you acknowledge that the information you provide will be transferred to Mailchimp for processing in accordance with their [terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/) and [privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

We also use Google Analytics to track site usage. We use the AnonymizeIP function of Analytics to ensure that Google does not store your full IP address. If you do not want your information tracked, please see this page on setting up [Do Not Track](https://allaboutdnt.com/) on your browser.

You can request that your information be removed at any time. 

We will retain your information indefinitely or until you ask us to remove it. 

## When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on our site.

## How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you sign up for our newsletter or leave a comment to send you a periodic newsletter that you can opt out of any time, or to respond to a query.

## How do we protect your information?

We only provide articles and information. We never ask for credit card numbers.

We use regular Malware Scanning.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.

### Removing Your Information

Simon Fairbairn is the data controller and he can be contacted through our [contact page](https://www.neverendingvoyage.com/contact-us/). You can remove your information in the following ways:

  * If you would like your email address deleted from our mailing list, please click the Unsubscribe link at the bottom of any newsletters you may have received.
  * If you would like a comment removed, please [email us](https://www.neverendingvoyage.com/contact-us/) from the same email address used to make the comment (for verification) with a link to the page of the comment you would like removed.

## Do we use ‘cookies’?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) and that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since each browser is a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you turn cookies off, some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly. 

## Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when its release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## Third-party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## Google

We have implemented the following:

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

Opting out:

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.
